Sarah Rosanna Busch

101-55 Bay Street, Victoria BC V9A 6X9, 250-217-4370, annarose0113@gmail.com

Skills and Attributes

javascript creative
node curious
json smart
html hard working
css/scss friendly
svg team player

About Me

I am a software developer whose expertise is primarily in custom web-based user interfaces for embedded systems. I changed career paths from chemistry six years ago, because software development is the perfect fit for my creativity and analytical thinking. I have a passion for learning and developing new skills, and like to work independently within a collaborative team to produce a quality product. You can check out some of my code at https://github.com/sarahRosannaBusch, which is mostly school projects and experiments, plus a site I'm currently working on: centripetalphotography.com.

I'm originally from Ontario, and have lived in Victoria since 2009, where I love to cycle, kayak, drink beer, and play boardgames with my friends. Feel free to follow me on <u>facebook</u> or <u>instagram</u> if you want to learn a little more about me.

Current Employment

- **UI Developer** <u>Quester Tangent</u>, Saanichton BC (2017-present)
 - Primary responsibilities include software design, implementation, and oversight of front-end development for on-train monitoring and control systems and passenger information systems, based on a combination of graphic designs, wireframes, and functional requirements
 - Design and develop a configurable, modular, testable, and extendable web UI framework for touchscreen and desktop, that can be translated to any language and logs all user interactions, including its node.js server and API
 - Define and document data structures, requests, and commands, passed between the UI and native
 C/C++ application along with supporting unit tests
 - Plan and assign tasks for 3-5 developers in a typically two-week sprint cycle using JIRA, in support of regular software release targets, and in coordination with team leads for the rest of our twelve person application team
 - Participate in rigorous code reviews using Perforce Helix and Swarm, and ensure promoted commits fulfill their requirements and are ready for testing and release
 - Support development, maintenance, and release of all software products/projects at any stage of their lifecycle, as needed
 - Mentor and train junior developers and co-op students as the resident javascript expert
 - o Contribute to software documentation according to IEEE standards, and help maintain our internal wiki

Education

- Electronics and Computer Engineering Technology Diploma Camosun College, Victoria BC (2014-2017)
 - Constructed electronic devices and circuits with embedded environments; learned many programming languages including C, C#, C++, HTML/CSS/Javascript, VHDL, LabView, and Assembly; used a wide variety of development environments and debugging tools including *Visual Studio*, *Quartus*, *Eclipse*, *CubeMX*, *MPLab*, *Arduino*, and *Particle*
- Chemical Engineering Technology Diploma <u>Seneca College</u>, Toronto ON (2005-2009)
 - Studied the fundamentals of theoretical chemistry, and practiced analytical lab techniques and chemical instrumentation
- High-School Diploma Fort Frances High-School, Fort Frances ON (1999-2003)
 - o Honor roll, french immersion, band, drama club, volleyball

Past Work History

- Teacher's Assistant and Lab Prep Tech Camosun College, Victoria BC (2015-2017)
 - Assisted with the TEAC course for high school students and helped the prep room staff when they were short handed
- Electronics Service Technician (Co-op) Forest Technology Services, Victoria BC (2016)
 - Serviced and repaired fire-weather sensors using high-reliability soldering techniques and basic programming skills, according to ISO standards; met tight deadlines
- Chemist Axys Analytical Services, Sidney BC (2009-2013)
 - Prepared environmental samples for ultra-trace analysis, including homogenization, extraction, and chromatographic columning; trained and supported new employees
- Chemist (Co-op) Ontario Ministry of the Environment, Toronto ON (2007)
 - Prepared environmental samples for analysis of persistent organic pollutants, including homogenization, extraction and chromatographic columning
- Chemist (Co-op) Experchem Laboratories, Toronto ON (2006)
 - Performed quality assurance analysis on pharmaceutical products
- Casual Labourer TLC Builders, Student Works, others (2003-2017)
 - Carpentry, painting, etc.